Noah Taiga Endo Software Engineer

M noah.taigameier@gmail.com

Tokyo, Japan

German & Japanese citizenship

in www.linkedin.com/in/noah-taiga-endo

https://github.com/Octosub

ABOUT ME

With a background in analytics and professional experience in customer service, I bring a rich cultural perspective and adaptability from my bilingual upbringing. Recently graduating from Le Wagon's web development boot camp, I'm proficient in Ruby on Rails, React, and familiar with modern workflows of the tech industry. Now I'm highly motivated to apply my skills in Tokyo's IT industry.

PROJECTS

CIET - Can I Eat This?

Lead Developer

An application for foreign vegans/vegetarians in Japan to scan food products and check if it meets their dietary restrictions.

//Ruby on Rails, Google API's, DeepL API, Stimulus JS, HTML, CSS, Stimulus JS, Heroku

Quanki 🛮

With Quanki you can easily create a quiz from a pdf file of your notes, lecture slides, academic texts etc.. //React, Ruby on Rails, OpenAl API, Postgresql

EDUCATION

01/2024 - 03/2024 Fullstack Web Development Bootcamp

LeWagon Tokyo Japan

> 9-weeks full-time intensive training of the technical skills needed for a successful career in tech, learning how to develop great products in teams using

modern workflows at the #1 web development bootcamp in the world.

2017 - 2022Bachelor of Arts, Philosophy

Germany University of Konstanz

AWARDS

Builders Weekend Hackathon - Morph Prize 2 04/2024

Received a prize for the best project built within 3 days from one of the sponsors

of the hackathon.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

04/2020 - 10/2020 Mercedes-Benz Japan Co., Ltd.

Compliance Trainee Tokyo, Japan

• Data protection for customers in accordance with the GDPR.

06/2022 - 12/2023

Guidepoint Japan Research Associate Tokyo, Japan

• Conducting effective analysis on various topics to consult clients in a fast

paced working environment

SKILLS

Backend Frontend **Tools**

Ruby on Rails, Webscraping & HTML, CSS/SCSS, Javascript Git/Github, Heroku, Figma API's, ActiveRecord & SQL, CSV (Stimulus JS & React)

LANGUAGES

English Japanese German

Native/Bilingual proficiency Native/Bilingual proficiency Bilingual proficiency